<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter number="19">
	<title>RATIFICATION AND SIGNATURE</title>
	<article number="110">
		<para>
			<list>
				<item>
					<para>The present Charter shall be ratified by the signatory states in accordance with their respective constitutional processes.</para>
				</item>
				<item>
					<para>The ratifications shall be deposited with the Government of the United States of America, which shall notify all the signatory states of each deposit as well as the Secretary-General of the Organization when he has been appointed.</para>
				</item>
				<item>
					<para>The present Charter shall come into force upon the deposit of ratifications by the Republic of China, France, the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, and the United States of America, and by a majority of the other signatory states. A protocol of the ratifications deposited shall thereupon be drawn up by the Government of the United States of America which shall communicate copies thereof to all the signatory states.</para>
				</item>
				<item>
					<para>The states signatory to the present Charter which ratify it after it has come into force will become original Members of the United Nations on the date of the deposit of their respective ratifications.</para>
				</item>
			</list>
		</para>
	</article>
	<article number="111">
		<para>The present Charter, of which the Chinese, French, Russian, English, and Spanish texts are equally authentic, shall remain deposited in the archives of the Government of the United States of America. Duly certified copies thereof shall be transmitted by that Government to the Governments of the other signatory states.</para>
		<para>IN FAITH WHEREOF the representatives of the Governments of the United Nations have signed the present Charter.</para>
		<para>DONE at the city of San Francisco the twenty-sixth day of June, one thousand nine hundred and forty-five.</para>
	</article>
</chapter>
