<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter number="9">
	<title>INTERNATIONAL ECONOMIC AND SOCIAL CO-OPERATION</title>
	<article number="55">
		<para>
				With a view to the creation of conditions of stability and well-being which are necessary for peaceful and friendly relations among nations based on respect for the principle of equal rights and self-determination of peoples, the United Nations shall promote:
				<list type="running">
				<item>
					<para>higher standards of living, full employment, and conditions of economic and social progress and development;</para>
				</item>
				<item>
					<para>solutions of international economic, social, health, and related problems; and international cultural and educational cooperation; and</para>
				</item>
				<item>
					<para>universal respect for, and observance of, human rights and fundamental freedoms for all without distinction as to race, sex, language, or religion.</para>
				</item>
			</list>
		</para>
	</article>
	<article number="56">
		<para>
				All Members pledge themselves to take joint and separate action in co-operation with the Organization for the achievement of the purposes set forth in Article 55.
			</para>
	</article>
	<article number="57">
		<para>
			<list>
				<item>
					<para>The various specialized agencies, established by intergovernmental agreement and having wide international responsibilities, as defined in their basic instruments, in economic, social, cultural, educational, health, and related fields, shall be brought into relationship with the United Nations in accordance with the provisions of Article 63.</para>
				</item>
				<item>
					<para>Such agencies thus brought into relationship with the United Nations are hereinafter referred to as specialized agencies.</para>
				</item>
			</list>
		</para>
	</article>
	<article number="58">
		<para>
				The Organization shall make recommendations for the co-ordination of the policies and activities of the specialized agencies.
			</para>
	</article>
	<article number="59">
		<para>
				The Organization shall, where appropriate, initiate negotiations among the states concerned for the creation of any new specialized agencies required for the accomplishment of the purposes set forth in Article 55.
			</para>
	</article>
	<article number="60">
		<para>
				Responsibility for the discharge of the functions of the Organization set forth in this Chapter shall be vested in the General Assembly and, under the authority of the General Assembly, in the Economic and Social Council, which shall have for this purpose the powers set forth in Chapter X. 
			</para>
	</article>
</chapter>
