<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter number="8">
	<title>REGIONAL ARRANGEMENTS</title>
	<article number="52">
		<para>
			<list>
				<item>
					<para>Nothing in the present Charter precludes the existence of regional arrangements or agencies for dealing with such matters relating to the maintenance of international peace and security as are appropriate for regional action provided that such arrangements or agencies and their activities are consistent with the Purposes and Principles of the United Nations.</para>
				</item>
				<item>
					<para>The Members of the United Nations entering into such arrangements or constituting such agencies shall make every effort to achieve pacific settlement of local disputes through such regional arrangements or by such regional agencies before referring them to the Security Council.</para>
				</item>
				<item>
					<para>The Security Council shall encourage the development of pacific settlement of local disputes through such regional arrangements or by such regional agencies either on the initiative of the states concerned or by reference from the Security Council.</para>
				</item>
				<item>
					<para>This Article in no way impairs the application of Articles 34 and 35.</para>
				</item>
			</list>
		</para>
	</article>
	<article number="53">
		<para>
			<list>
				<item>
					<para>The Security Council shall, where appropriate, utilize such regional arrangements or agencies for enforcement action under its authority. But no enforcement action shall be taken under regional arrangements or by regional agencies without the authorization of the Security Council, with the exception of measures against any enemy state, as defined in paragraph 2 of this Article, provided for pursuant to Article 107 or in regional arrangements directed against renewal of aggressive policy on the part of any such state, until such time as the Organization may, on request of the Governments concerned, be charged with the responsibility for preventing further aggression by such a state.</para>
				</item>
				<item>
					<para>The term enemy state as used in paragraph 1 of this Article applies to any state which during the Second World War has been an enemy of any signatory of the present Charter.</para>
				</item>
			</list>
		</para>
	</article>
	<article number="54">
		<para>
				The Security Council shall at all times be kept fully informed of activities undertaken or in contemplation under regional arrangements or by regional agencies for the maintenance of international peace and security.
			</para>
	</article>
</chapter>
